Ma, Ma, calm down. Listen to me. I know it says click with the mouse...
Maman, calme-toi. Ils te disent de cliquer sur la souris,
...but on a laptop, the trackpad is the mouse.
mais sur un portable, le pavé tactile est la souris.
Now, put your finger on it. No, doesn't matter which finger.
Pose ton doigt dessus. Non, peu importe quel doigt.
Good choice.
Très bon choix.
Yeah, now move it down to your e-mail icon.
Déplace-le sur l'icône de ta boîte e-mail.
Yeah, the little envelope.
Oui, la petite enveloppe.
What do you mean what does it look like? It looks like an envelope!
A quoi ça ressemble ? A une enveloppe!
Fine, you don't like the computer, don't use it.
Si tu n'aimes pas l‘ordinateur, ne t'en sers pas.
Sure, we can exchange it for a salad spinner. Goodbye.
On l'échangera contre une essoreuse à salade. Au revoir.
That's a Hanukkah present you're regretting, huh?
Tu regrettes ton cadeau de Hanoukkah, pas vrai ?
Yeah, I won't say that all senior citizens who can't master technology...
Je ne dis pas qu‘il faut fouetter en public tous les seniors
...should be publicly flogged, but if we made an example of one or two...
qui ne maîtrisent pas la technologie, mais si on faisait un exemple,
...it might give the others incentive to try harder.
cela motiverait les autres à faire un effort.
I had a great idea. You know how we're always having...
J'ai eu une super idée. Vous savez quand on doit résoudre
...to stop and solve differential equations...
des équations différentielles quand on fait
...like when you do Fourier analysis or using the Schrodinger equation?
une transformation de Fourier ou une équation de Schrädinger ?
Howard doesn't. He's only an engineer.
Howard ne sait pas. Il est ingénieur.
I think we could write a little app that would use handwriting recognition...
On pourrait écrire une application qui reconnaitrait l‘écriture
...then run it through a symbolic evaluation engine.
et qui utiliserait un moteur d'évaluation symbolique.
You just use your smartphone, take a picture of the equation, and bam!
Vous prenez une photo de l‘équation et bingo.
You know what's a great app? The one that makes fart noises.
J‘adore l‘application qui fait des bruits de pets.
You know, Leonard, that's actually a valid idea. Very good.
C‘est une idée pertinente, Leonard. Bravo.
Can you say that and not make it sound like I'm a cat...
Tu peux éviter de me dire ça comme si j‘étais un chat
...who learned how to use the toilet?
qui venait d‘apprendre à utliser les toilettes ?
No. The two achievements are equally surprising...
Non. Ce sont deux exploits tout aussi surprenants
...and equally admirable.
et tout aussi admirables.
Though if pressed, I'd have to give a slight edge to the cat.
Même si j'ai une légère préférence pour le chat.
I'll save you the pain and nervousness of waiting for the answer.
Je vais t'éviter le stress lié à l‘attente de ma réponse.
I agree to be part of your project. Congratulations.
J‘accepte de participer à ton projet. Félicitations.
Ha, ha. Yay for me.
YoupL
What about you? I can't promise anything...
Et vous ? Je ne vous promets rien,
...but people do make money off stuff like this.
mais certains gagnent de l'argent avec ça.
A few extra bucks would be nice.
J'aimerais bien un peu d‘argent.
-Could move out of my mother's house. -Where would you go?
- Je partirais de chez ma mére. - Où irais-tu ?
I always dreamed about building a little place of my own over the garage.
Je rêve de faire construire mon chez—moi au-dessus du garage.
You know, ifl made more money, I could take time off...
J'emmènerais des jolies filles
...and give pretty girls submarine rides.
faire un tour en sous-marin.
What's that, some weird sex thing?
C‘est quoi, un délire sexuel ?
No. You take girls underwater in your private submarine...
Non, tu emmènes des filles dans ton sous—marin privé
...and you show them fish.
et tu leur montres des poissons.
Why does everything have to be dirty with you?
Tu as vraiment l'esprit mal placé.
I think we could work on this at night and maybe in a couple of weeks...
On peut y travailler le soir, et dans deux semaines
-...we'll have ourselves an app to sell. -Sounds like we're in business.
- on pourra vendre notre application. - C‘est une affaire conclue.
-I think we should capture this moment. -Yeah, let's do it.
- On devrait capturer cet instant. - Oui.
Was that the best 99 cents I ever spent or what?
Je n'ai jamais aussi bien dépensé 99 cents.
I checked the App Store.
J‘ai vérifié.
No one is doing handwriting recognition differential equation solving.
Personne n‘a fait d‘application de résolution d'équation.
Oh, dear Lord, shush.
Doux Jésus, chut.
-What? -You have so few good ideas, Leonard.
- Quoi ? - Tu as si peu de bonnes idées.
And you're just gonna spill the beans in front of an outsider?
Et tu vas tout balancer devant une étrangère ?
Who, me?
Qui, moi ?
Sheldon, I don't think Penny cares about handwriting-recognition based--
Penny ne s‘intéresse pas àla reconnaissance d‘écriture...
-She's not going to steal our idea. -What idea?
- Elle ne va pas voler notre idée. - Quelle idée ?
-We're gonna write-- -[SINGSONG] The Prairie sky
On va écrire…
-Okay, stop, stop. -Of Texas
D‘accord, ça suffit.
Whatever your secret is, I'm sure it's boring. So I'm not interested.
Votre secret est sûrement barbant. Ça ne m‘intéresse pas.
Well, it's not boring at all. You see, in higher-order mathematics...
Ce n‘est pas barbant. En mathématiques supérieures,
-...there are certain sets of equations-- -Bored.
- certaines équations… - Barbant.
-Satisfied? -[IN NORMAL VOICE] Hardly.
- Satisfait ? - Pas vraiment.
Consider this unlikely but very plausible scenario.
Voici un scénario improbable mais plausible.
A young woman alone in the big city.
Une jeune femme seule dans la grande ville.
Her ridiculous dream of becoming an actress...
Son rêve ridicule de devenir actrice
...lies shattered about her.
gît à ses pieds.
-Hey, wait a minute. -Hang on, let's see where he's going.
- Attends un peu. - Ecoutons où il veut en venir.
Then it hits her, how is she going to survive?
Puis une question la frappe, comment va-t-elle survivre ?
But she has no prospects, no marketable skills.
Elle n‘a aucune perspective, aucun talent exploitable.
And then one day, she meets a group of geniuses...
Un jour, elle rencontre un groupe de génies
...and their friend Howard.
et leur ami Howard.
-Hey, l-- -Hang on, let's see where he's going.
- Je... - Ecoutons où il veut en venir.
She befriends them, and then lies in wait until they reveal a marketable idea...
Elle devient leur amie et attend qu‘ils lui révèlent une idée vendable
...which she steals and sells to the highest bidder.
qu'elle leur voie et revend au plus offrant.
That is ridiculous.
C‘est absurde.
Is it? Let's see you come up with an explanation...
Tu crois ? Alors explique—moi
...as to why this woman hangs out with us all the time.
pourquoi cette femme passe son temps avec nous.
I've already mooched dinner off you guys.
Vous m'avez déjà filé à bouffer.
-I don't need to listen to this. -There's your answer, free food.
- Je n'ai pas besoin de vous écouter. - Pour la nourriture gratuite.
All right, I've taken the liberty of drafting these workflow charts...
J'ai pris la liberté d‘établir ces plannings de travail
...which outline our duties and the path we will follow...
pour définir nos tâches et la route à suivre
...as we develop our groundbreaking new app.
pour développer notre application d'avant-garde.
Hey. Why am I in charge of phone support?
Pourquoi je m'occupe du suivi téléphonique ?
Seems a bit racist.
C‘est un peu raciste.
A customer service representative with an Indian accent...
Un responsable clientèle avec un accent indien
...will create the impression we're a vast enterprise...
donnera l'impression qu'on est une grande entreprise
...that uses overseas call centers.
avec des centres d'appels à l‘étranger.
Duly noted, Steve from Wichita.
C‘est bien noté, Steve de Wichita.
Hey, why am I listed as your executive assistant?
Pourquoi je suis ton assistant de direction ?
Because the word secretary has fallen into disrepute.
Parce que le mot secrétaire n‘est plus très bien vu.
Oh, FYI, my mother's birthday is coming up.
C‘est bientôt l'anniversaire de ma mére.
I'm going to need you to pick up a present.
Tu devras lui trouver un cadeau.
Okay, we need to stop for a minute.
Arrêtons un instant.
We can talk during break. We have one coming up at midnight.
On parlera àla pause qui est prévue à minuit.
-And we'll need snacks. -Sheldon, you're not in charge.
- Il faudra prévoir un encas. - Sheldon, tu ne diriges pas.
-lt's my idea. I'm in charge. -Oh, of course, you are.
- C‘est mon idée. Je dirigé. - Bien sûr.
Look at the organizational chart. You're clearly listed as founder.
Regarde l‘organigramme. Tu es le fondateur.
Yes, and you're listed as chief executive officer...
Oui, et tu es le président-directeur-général,
...chief financial officer and chief operating officer.
le directeur financier et le directeur général.
You missed chief science officer, chairman of the board and...
Tu as oublié directeur scientifique, président du conseil
-...head of the Secret Santa committee. -Okay.
- et chef du comité de Noël. - D‘accord.
You need to get clear on this right now: lam in charge of this project.
Tirons les choses au clair. Je dirige ce projet.
All right. I'm not going to argue with you.
D‘accord. Je ne vais pas discuter.
Sheldon Cooper is nothing if not a team player.
Sheldon Cooper est un simple membre de l‘équipe.
Dr. Hofstadter, you have the con.
Dr Hofstadter, tu mènes la barque.
Thank you. I thought we might start...
Merci. Je pense qu'on pourrait commencer
-...by talking about the user interface. -Dear Lord, we're doomed.
- par parler de l'interface. - Doux Jésus, on est fichus.
So this button here will allow you to scan a new equation...
Ce bouton permet de scanner une nouvelle équation,
...but over here, you can press this...
mais en appuyant sur celui—ci,
...and just substitute new values for the coefficients.
on peut changer la valeur des coefficients.
Ha, ha. Good one, boss.
Très drôle, patron.
-What? -This diagram.
- Quoi ? - Ce schéma.
Well, I assume you were opening with ajoke.
Je suppose que tu commences par une blague.
It certainly buoyed up this employee's esprit de corps.
Bonne idée pour stimuler l'esprit corporatif.
It's not ajoke. It's the real design.
Ce n‘est pas une blague. C‘est le projet.
In that case, may I offer 27 little tweaks to make it slightly less embarrassing?
Puis-je faire 27 petites modifs pour que ce soit moins gênant ?
Sheldon, I think this will work. Let's just try it my way.
Sheldon, ça peut marcher. Faisons à ma façon.
Oh, I'm sorry. I assumed that you wanted...
Pardon. J'ai cru que tu voulais
...candid truth-telling from your employees.
des employés candides te disant la Vérité.
But I realize now, you want the mindless nattering...
Mais tu veux seulement des pies bavardes
...of complacent yes-men.
qui disent amen à tout ce que tu fais.
-Are you done? -If you say so, boss.
- Tu as fini ? - Comme tu veux, patron.
Right now, this button-press event is triggering a dummy procedure call.
Quand on appuie sur ce bouton, on lance une procédure fictive.
How about this for the app name?
J'ai pensé à un nom pour l'application.
The Surprisingly Helpful Equation-Linked Differential...
Le super calculateur d‘équations différentielles optimisé
...Optimized Numerator.
à numérotation.
So it spells "Sheldon."
Ça fait Sheldon.
Does it? A happy accident.
Vraiment ? Quelle coïncidence.
-We're not doing names now. Howard? -Like I was saying...
- On n'en est pas au nom. Howard ? - Comme je disais,
...now, it's a dummy procedure. Eventually, it will drop us in--
c‘est une procédure fictive. Elle nous enverra sur...
If we're not going to give it a name...
Si on ne lui donne pas de nom,
...can we at least give it a secret code designation?
peut-on au moins lui donner un code secret ?
-No. -Hear me out.
- Non. - Écoute-moi.
The atomic bomb was the Manhattan Project...
La bombe atomique s'appelait le Projet Manhattan,
...Windows 95 was originally Project Chicago.
Windows 95 était à l‘origine le Projet Chicago.
For our app, I would humbly suggest Project Nodlehs.
Pour notre application, je propose le Projet Nodlehs.
That's just Sheldon backwards.
C‘est Sheldon à l‘envers.
Another happy accident.
Une autre coïncidence.
We're not wasting time with names right now.
On ne va pas perdre de temps avec un nom maintenant.
-ls that decision open for discussion? -No.
- Est-ce ouvert au débat ? - Non.
Is the decision to not discuss...
La décision de ne pas en débattre
-...open for discussion? -No.
- est-elie ouverte au débat ? - Non.
Again, right now...
Donc, pour l'instant,
...it's a dummy procedure, but eventually, it will drop us--
c‘est une procédure fictive, mais elle…
I call for a vote of no confidence and a change in leadership.
Je demande un vote pour changer de directeur.
-Sheldon, stop it. -When in the course of human events...
- Arrête. - Dans l'histoire de l‘humanité,
...it becomes necessary to dissolve the bonds...
quand il devient nécessaire de dissoudre les liens
-...that tie three scientists-- -Enough, Sheldon.
- entre trois scientifiques... - Ça suffit, Sheldon.
Let's get to the vote. Show of hands...
Passons au vote. Tous ceux s'opposant
...all opposed to Leonard and his reign of tyranny:
au règne tyrannique de Leonard, levez la main.
-Okay, that's it, you're fired. -Really?
- Ça suffit, tu es viré. - Vraiment ?
Why?
Pourquoi ?
Because you're impossible to work with.
Car c‘est impossible de travailler avec toi.
And is that open for discussion?
Est-ce ouvert au débat ?
-What are you doing? -Oh, good morning, shoemaker.
- Que fais-tu ? - Bonjour, M. le cordonnier.
I think you'll be pleased with what the elves were up to last night.
Les lutins ont bien travaillé hier soir.
But I fired you.
Je t'ai renvoyé.
Oh, I know. I'm now an independent contractor.
Je sais. Je travaille en indépendant.
No, you are now nothing.
Non, tu ne fais rien du tout.
You have no connection to this project whatsoever.
Tu n'as plus aucun lien avec ce projet.
But I made it better.
Mais je l'ai amélioré.
I don't want it better. I want it my way.
Je ne le veux pas mieux. Je le veux à ma façon.
Well, that speaks volumes, doesn't it?
Ca en dit long sur toi.
All right, I suppose I'll go put on my bus pants.
Trés bien. Je vais mettre mon pantalon de bus.
-What the hell are bus pants? -They are pants one wears...
- C‘est quoi ? - C‘est un pantalon que l'on porte
...over regular pants when one sits on bus seats...
sur un autre pantalon pour s‘asseoir sur un siège de bus
...that other people have previously sat on.
où d'autres gens se sont déjà assis.
But, perhaps, from your lofty heights atop the corporate ladder...
Depuis les hauteurs vertigineuses du sommet de l‘échelle sociale,
...you've lost touch with the struggles of the common man.
tu as perdu toute réalité des combats de l‘homme ordinaire.
Look, I'm still happy to drive you to work.
Je serai ravi de te conduire au travail.
Nothing's changed in that regard. We're still roommates, still friends.
Rien n‘a changé. On est toujours colocataires et amis.
Except you identified me, your best friend...
Sauf que tu m‘a identifié, ton meilleur ami,
...as a gangrenous limb...
comme un membre gangréné
...that needed to be severed from the organism and tossed.
qui fallait séparer de l‘organisme etjeter.
The desperate act of a little man with a big Napoleon complex.
C‘est l'acte désespéré d'un homme avec un gros complexe de Napoléon.
You know what? Go put on your bus pants.
Tu sais quoi ? Va enfiler ton pantalon de bus.
Mm, last night, I had a dream we got so rich from the app...
Hier soir, j'ai rêvé qu'on devenait si riches grâce à l‘application
...you and I bought matching side-by-side mansions.
qu'on achetait des manoirs mitoyens.
But there was a secret tunnel...
Mais il y avait un tunnel secret
...connecting your front yard to my back yard.
qui reliait ton jardin de devant à mon jardin de derrière.
What do you think that means?
Cela signifie quoi ?
It means after we play handball, I'm showering at home.
Après notre match de hand, je prendrai ma douche chez moi.
Oh, good morning, friend Howard, friend Raj.
Bonjour, ami Howard, ami Raj.
I see you gentlemen are enjoying beverages.
Je vois que vous dégustez de délicieux breuvages.
Perhaps, they would taste better out of these.
Ils seront peut-être encore meilleurs dans ces tasses.
-"World's Greatest Astrophysicist"? -Don't thank me, you earned it.
-"Le plus grand astrophysicien ?" - Ne me remercie pas, tu l'as mérité.
"Howard Wolowitz."
”Howard Wolowitz."
Why not "World's Greatest Engineer"?
Pourquoi pas "Le plus grand ingénieur ?"
Oh, I'm sorry, I typed that into the label maker...
Désolé, je l‘avais tapé,
...but I just couldn't press enter. Now down to business.
mais je n'ai pas pu appuyer sur Entrée. Parlons affaires.
What would it take for you to abandon Leonard...
Que vous faudrait-il pour abandonner Leonard
...and join me in a rival company?
et rejoindre ma société rivale ?
Unless, of course, mugs are sufficient.
Sauf, bien sûr, si ces tasses suffisent.
In which case, welcome aboard.
Dans lequel cas, bienvenue à bord.
-We're not quitting on Leonard. -I understand. Your loyalty is admirable.
- On ne va pas abandonner Leonard. - Votre loyauté est admirable.
But what if I were to up the ante?
Mais si je montais la mise ?
What are you talking about?
De quoi tu parles ?
Monogrammed key chains with a built-in laser pointer.
Des porte-clés à monogramme avec pointeur laser intégré.
No?
Non ?
How about can cozies emblazoned with our university mascot?
Et ces chaussettes à canettes décorées de notre mascotte ?
Go Beavers.
Allez les Beavers.
I'll be back.
Je reviens.
Okay, let's try this one.
Essayons celle—ci.
Spherical Hankel function.
Fonction sphérique de Hankel.
Hold on.
Attends.
-That's it! -Yes! Eureka!
- C‘est ça! - Eurêka!
We agreed when it was "eureka" time, we were all gonna say it together.
On avait dit qu'on s'écrirait "eurêka" ensemble.
-Fine, let's say it together. -No, the moment has passed.
- D‘accord, disons-Ie ensemble. - Non, ça ne marche plus.
Greetings, gentlemen.
Bonjour, messieurs.
How goes your little project?
Comment avance votre petit projet ?
You mean Project Lenwoloppali?
Le Project Lenwoloppali ?
A combination of all your names. Very clever.
Une combinaison de vos noms. Trés malin.
I assume "Koothranardowitz" was taken.
Je suppose que "Koothranardowitz" était déjà pris.
We're scanning equations and getting good results.
On scanne des équations et on a de bons résultats.
Oh, well, then by all means, carry on.
Je vous en prie, continuez.
I wouldn't wanna impede your progress.
Je ne voudrais pas vous gêner.
Howard, did you solve the install time problem?
As-tu résolu le problème du temps d'installation ?
No, it's tricky. I'm gonna try having it pick up the libraries--
Non. Je vais essayer de prendre dans les bases…
What are you doing?
A quoi joues-tu ?
Playing the theremin.
Je joue du thérémine.
No, I mean, what are you doing with a theremin?
Mais que fais-tu avec un thérémine ?
Playing it.
J'yjoue.
I've loved the theremin from the moment I heard original Star Trek theme.
Depuis le théme de Star Trek, j‘adore cet instrument.
And it's been killing me that it just sits in my closet gathering dust.
C‘est vraiment dommage qu'il prenne la poussière dans mon placard.
-Sheldon, we're working here. -That's all right.
- Sheldon, on travaille. - Ça ne me dérange pas.
I can barely hear you over my theremin.
Je ne vous entends presque pas.
Well, that was a little uncalled for.
Voici qui est totalement injustifié.
No, that was completely called for. We need quiet.
Non, c‘est tout à fait justifié. On a besoin de calme.
So your project is more important than mine?
Ton projet est plus important que le mien ?
Well, seeing as your project is to sabotage my project, yes.
Puisque ton projet est de saboter le mien, oui.
Don't beat around the bush, Leonard.
Ne tourne pas autour du pot.
If you don't want me here, just say the word and I'll leave.
Si tu ne veux pas de moi ici, tu n'as qu'à le dire.
Could have beaten around the bush a little.
Il aurait pu tourner un peu autour du pot.
What you doing, trying to contact your home planet?
Que fais-tu ? Tu contactes ta planète ?
I'm practicing my theremin.
Je m'entraine au thérémine.
Something got you down there, Sheldon?
Tu as une raison pour être la, Sheldon ?
Leonard kicked me out of my own apartment.
Leonard m‘a mis àla porte de chez moi.
-And his app team. -Oh, honey, I'm sorry.
- Avec son équipe. - Je suis désolée.
He wouldn't drive me to work today. I had to wear my bus pants.
Il ne m‘a pas emmené au travail. J'ai dû porter mon pantalon de bus.
-ls that so? -Yes, and they're still sticky.
- Vraiment ? - Oui, et il colle encore.
Probably gonna have to throw them away.
Je vais sûrement devoir le jeter.
Hey, you don't need Leonard and his app.
Tu n'as pas besoin de Leonard.
You can make one with me.
Tu peux faire une application avec moi.
With you?
Avec toi ?
-Seriously, I have a great idea for one. -ls it better than your idea...
- J'ai une super idée. - Est-elie meilleure que ton idée
...to move to Los Angeles and become a famous actress?
de venir à Los Angeles pour devenir une actrice célèbre ?
When you see someone wearing shoes you like...
Quand tu vois des chaussures qui te plaisent,
...you snap a picture and the app goes on the Internet...
tu les photographies et l‘application te dit
-...to find out where you can buy them. -That's your app idea?
- où tu peux les acheter. - C‘est ça ton idée ?
-You don't like it? -I didn't say that. But no, I don't.
- Ça ne te plait pas ? - Je n'ai pas dit ça. Non.
-Why not? -Oh, Penny, where do I begin?
- Pourquoi ? - Par où commencer, Penny ?
The simple-mindedness of your idea...
La naïveté de ton idée
...is exceeded only by its crass consumerism and banality.
n‘est surpassée que par sa banalité et son consumérisme grossier.
And Leonard didn't wanna work with you, imagine that.
Dire que Leonard n‘a pas voulu travailler avec toi, incroyable.
I know, it's baffling.
Je sais, c‘est déroutant.
Sheldon, I'm gonna make some cocoa. Do you want some?
Je vais faire du chocolat chaud. Tu en veux ?
-Do you make it with milk or water? -Milk.
- Avec de l‘eau ou du lait? - Avec du lait.
-Real cocoa? -That's what it says on the packet.
- Du vrai cacao ? - C‘est écrit sur la boîte.
-You have those little marshmallows? -No, sorry.
- Tu as des petits marshmallows ? - Non, désolée.
-Well, I suppose it's appropriate. -What does that mean?
- C‘est de circonstance. - Comment ça ?
A disappointing drink for a disappointing day.
Une boisson décevante pour une journée décevante.
Look. Twenty people from the university...
Vingt personnes de l'université
...have already signed up for our private beta.
se sont inscrites pour notre version bêta.
I tell you, the Lenwoloppali Differential Equation Scanner meets a real need.
Il y a une vraie demande pour le scanner Lenwoloppali.
We've got a hit.
- C‘est de l‘or. - A combien devrait-on le vendre ?
Based on the fact that our potential market...
Etant donné que le marché potentiel se limite
...is about 70 or 80 guys, and you want a submarine...
à 70 ou 80 types, et que tu veux un sous-marin,
...l'd say about a million dollars a pop.
je dirais un million de dollars l'unité.
What if we put out a light version for half a million?
Faisons une version édulcorée à un demi million.
Get the word of mouth going.
Pour faire parler de nous.
Hi, I'm sorry to bother you guys...
Pardon de vous déranger,
...but you've gotta come take Sheldon back.
mais il faut que vous repreniez Sheldon.
-What's he doing in your apartment? -He was moping in the lobby...
- Que fait-il chez toi ? - Il déprimait dans l‘entrée,
...so I invited him over. I regret it.
alors je l'ai invité. Je le regrette.
Why do you regret--? Never mind, stupid question.
Pourquoi regrettes—tu... Laisse tomber, question bête.
Can't you just let him play until bedtime?
Laisse-Ie jouer jusqu‘à l‘heure du dodo.
We're not playing. This is real work.
On ne joue pas. On travaille.
We're gonna be hundredaires.
On va gagner des centaines de dollars.
Okay, what if I got him to apologize and promise to behave?
Et s'il s'excuse et qu'il promet de bien se tenir ?
Then I guess we would let him back on the app team.
On le laissera revenir dans l‘équipe.
While we're doing that, you could take an aerial tour of LA. on your flying pig.
Pendant ce temps, tu pourras survoler L.A. sur ton cochon volant.
Okay, wait right here.
D‘accord, ne bougez pas.
I'll tell you one thing...
Si je deviens riche,
...if I get rich, that's the kind of girl I wanna take on a submarine ride.
c‘est le genre de fille que je prendrai en sous-marin.
And yes, that time I meant it to be dirty.
Oui, c‘était salace cette fois.
Really?
C‘est vrai ?
Leonard wants me back?
Leonard veut que je revienne ?
Oh, yes. He says they are lost without you.
Oui, il dit qu'il est perdu sans toi.
Well, we sure saw that coming.
C‘était couru d‘avance.
-That's right. -You know what I'm going to do?
- C‘est vrai. - Tu sais ce que je vais faire ?
lam going to sit here and just let them stew.
Je vais rester ici et les laisser mariner.
No, no, no. You know, they have suffered enough.
Non, ils ont assez souffert.
You know, everybody's suffered enough.
Tout le monde a assez souffert.
The thing is...
Le problème,
...you're gonna have to offer him a face-saving way out of this.
c‘est qu'il faut le laisser s'en sortir la tête haute.
-How? -Say you're sorry.
- Comment ? - Dis—lui que tu es désolé.
Oh, no. Mrs. Mary Cooper didn't raise her no liars.
Non. Mme Mary Cooper n‘a pas élevé de menteurs.
Okay. Um, how about this? You know how you're always trying to learn...
D‘accord. Je sais. Tu essayes toujours d‘apprendre
...about sarcasm?
sur les sarcasmes, non ?
-No. -No?
- Non. - Non ?
l was being sarcastic.
J‘étais sarcastique.
Oh, good for you.
C‘est bien.
All you have to do is say you're sorry to Leonard...
Dis à Leonard que tu es désolé,
...but say it sarcastically.
mais de façon sarcastique.
Of course.
Bien sûr.
He will hear it as an attempt to mend fences...
Il entendra une tentative de réconciliation,
...as opposed to the withering condemnation you and I know it to be.
et non la condamnation cinglante que ce sera en réalité.
Yeah, that was my plan. All right. Come on. Let's go.
Oui, c‘était mon plan. Allons-y.
By the way, thank you for the delicious cocoa.
Merci pour ton délicieux chocolat chaud.
-Oh, you're welcome. -Oh, I'm getting good at this.
- De rien. - Je deviens vraiment doué.
Okay, now that you're back on the team let's get you caught up.
Maintenant que tu es revenu, on va t‘expliquer ce qu'on a fait.
Before you begin, let me say again how deeply sorry I am...
J'aimerais te redire à quel pointje suis désolé
...for my earlier behavior...
pour mon comportement,
...and how much I respect and admire your leadership.
et à quel point je te respecte etje t‘admire.
Thank you.
Merci.
So as you can see...
Comme tu peux le voir,
...not only can you store your favorite equations...
tu peux sauvegarder tes équations préférées,
...but you can forward them to your friends...
mais aussi les envoyer à tes amis
...or post them on Facebook right from the app.
ou les poster sur Facebook a partir de l'application.
-Well, I must say, I am impressed. -Thanks.
- Je suis impressionné. - Merci.
-You all have put in a lot of hard work. -We have.
- Vous avez travaillé dur. - C‘est vrai.
You have taken the most important step on the road to success:
Vous avez franchi la première étape sur la route du succés :
Learning what not to do. Now, let's start fresh.
apprendre ce qu'il ne faut pas faire. Reprenons tout.
Howard, we're going to need some tea.
Howard, il nous faudrait du thé.
Okay, these are Uggs.
Ce sont des Ugg.
These are Crocs.
Voici des Crocs.
-These are knockoff Manolo Blahniks. -Bored.
- Des fausses Manolo Blahnik. - Barbant.
You said it yourself, we have to create a database...
Tu as dit qu'il fallait créer une base de données
...before you can write an algo-thingy.
avant de pouvoir écrire un algo—machin.
Algorithm. You see, Penny, Alan Turing defines an algorithm--
Un algorithme. Alan Turing définit l‘algorithme...
Bored.
Barbant.
Okay. These are Steve Maddens.
Voici des Steve Madden.
These are Nine West.
Des Nine West.
These are Target. Oh, but don't they look like Chanel?
Des Target. Mais on dirait vraiment des Chanel.
-These are Michael Kors. -[SINGING] Nobody knows
Des Michael Kors. Des Roxy.
-Nobody knows -These are Seychelles.
Des Seychelles.
-My sorrow Oh, these are Betsy Johnson.
Des Betsy Johnson. Elles sont trop mignonnes.
[English - us - an]
[French]